John Meagher

Software Engineer and SRE with many years of experience in designing, building, and maintaining large scale distributed systems. Seeking a challenging role to utilize my diverse skills and experience in an innovative environment.

Remote or north Dallas, TX area LinkedIn: jpmeagher

john@jmeagher.net

EXPERIENCE

Instacart, Remote from Dallas, Tx — *Senior Software Engineer*

Jan 2018 - Feb 2024

- Designed and built a set of Elasticsearch clusters with transparent multi-region failover and the proxy that enabled it. This saved hours of downtime each year.
- Automated safe EC2 host level maintenance on a large cluster of PostgreSQL nodes to apply security updates and address cloud hardware problems.
- Designed and built an approach for handling imbalance that saved millions of dollars in hosting costs while maintaining system reliability.
- Chaos testing of systems including Redis, PostgreSQL, Golang, and Rust to improve overall reliability when host-level problems arise
- <u>Patent granted</u> for logging query structures while maintaining sizing information

Skills used: Golang, Rust, Ruby on Rails, Python, AWS EC2, AWS ECS, PostgreSQL, Elasticsearch, Redis, Datadog, Terraform

Twilio, San Francisco, CA — Senior Software Engineer

Apr 2017 - Dec 2017

- Developed automation for integrating Elasticsearch with internal deployment systems.
- Chaos testing and remediation of AWS EC2 hosted Elasticsearch.

Skills used: Scala, Kafka, Java, Elasticsearch, AWS EC2, Datadog

Twitter, San Francisco, CA — Senior Site Reliability Engineer

Sep 2014 - Mar 2017

- Automated day-to-day operations for <u>very large Hadoop clusters</u> (10k+ nodes) including removing nodes for maintenance and re-adding them to the clusters.
- Close work with Twitter networking team to maximize available bandwidth for Hadoop without impacting front-end traffic.

SKILLS

Languages: Golang, Rust, Ruby, Java, Scala, Python, Bash

Cloud/SAAS: AWS, EC2, ECS, Datadog, GitHub, PagerDuty, OpsGenie

Infrastructure: Terraform, Puppet

Software: Elasticsearch, Hadoop, PostgreSQL

LANGUAGES

Native English, Very beginner Spanish

- Develop server and service problem detection and remediation tools used to manage hundreds of thousands of servers and millions of task instances.
- Site-wide load testing to ensure uptime during high traffic load times.

Skills used: Scala, Hadoop, NoSQL (Cassandra-like system), Mesos/Aurora, Network QOS

LivingSocial, Washington, DC — Senior Big Data Engineer

Jun 2013 - Aug 2014

- Tripled processing capacity of existing Hadoop cluster through job scheduling optimizations and system tuning.
- Build Data Platform with vetted data sets for analyst use.

Lotame, Columbia, MD — Senior Software Engineer

Dec 2010 - May 2013

- Provide tools for ad-hoc data analysis using Pig and Hive
- Continually monitor and improve the batch data pipeline

Earlier jobs are not relevant anymore, but are available on LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/jpmeagher/

EDUCATION

Johns Hopkins University, Columbia, MD — *MSCS Computer Science*

Colorado School of Mines, Golden, CO — BSEE

Other Interests

• WSET level 3 candidate in wines and level 2 awarded with merit